Celebrate the untold story of an icon.
Whitney Houston: I Wanna Dance with Somebody is a music,
history, drama film directed by Kasi Lemmons.
The joyous, emotional, heartbreaking celebration of the life and music of
Whitney Houston, the greatest female R&B pop vocalist of all time.
Tracking her journey from obscurity to musical superstardom.
Whitney Houston, played by Naomi Ackie.
Bobby Brown, played by Ashton Sanders.
Clive Davis, played by Stanley Tucci.
Robyn Crawford, played by Nafessa Williams.
Gerry Griffith, played by Lance A. Williams.
Cissy Houston, played by Tamara Tunie.
Whitney Houston: I Wanna Dance with Somebody is a 2022 American biographical musical drama film directed by Kasi Lemmons, from a
screenplay by Anthony McCarten, based on the life and career of American pop icon and actress Whitney Houston.
The film stars Naomi Ackie as Houston with Stanley Tucci, Ashton Sanders, Tamara
Tunie, Nafessa Williams, and Clarke Peters in supporting roles.
An authorized biopic on Houston's life was announced in early 2020, with Ackie cast in the lead
role that December, and the rest of the cast signing on later the next year.
Produced on a $45 million budget, filming took place in
Massachusetts and New Jersey from August to December 2021.
Released in the United States on December 23, 2022, by Sony Pictures Releasing, the film received mixed reviews from critics, with praise
going to Ackie's performance and criticisms for the film's length, film editing and hewing of music biopic conventions.
It grossed $59.8 million, including more than $23
million in the domestic box office.
The film explores themes of musician, drug addiction,
biography, rhythm and blues (r&b), singer.
The tone is emotional.